# Alison Altomari

3823 Sunset Drive Los Angeles, CA 90027 (609) 306-1571 Altomari.Alison@gmail.com www.alaalison.com

Merging my rich experience in marketing with my unparalleled passion for food and agriculture, I excel at working directly with producers and purveyors to build successful brands and connecting the dots between consumers and real food.

# Professional Experience

#### Summerland

Head of Community

Los Angeles, CA January 2014 – Present

Tripled Summerland's customer base, social media following and brand recognition by launching pop up markets at Heath Ceramics, General Store, Echo Park Craft Fair and dinner series with One Fine Stay, Apartment A & Kitchen Surfing

Lead buyer for all third party marketplace goods and weekly local produce orders and selection at the Wednesday Santa Monica Farmers Market

Produces custom weekly content for website, social media, and customer collateral through recipe development and food photography and styling

#### California Olive Oil Council

Marketing Director

Berkeley, CA September 2012 – December 2013

Spearheaded the Council's first media dinners in San Francisco, New York and Baltimore; collaborating with reputable chefs to create menus, educating influential media guests and tastemakers, and generating awareness of the California olive oil industry

Strengthened the extra virgin certification program by implementing new evaluation methods for the taste panel and oversaw the certification of 450+ oils, training as a professional taster

Successfully completed redesign of the council's website and logo; transforming the brand image as well as membership communications

#### Monvinic Restaurant

Stage (Culinary Apprentice)
Barcelona, Spain January – April 2012

Gained an education in the Spanish language as well as authentic Catalan cuisine by training under each kitchen station, reporting directly to the executive chef

Facilitated the weekly produce orders and selection from 82 local food purveyors, visiting local markets and live seafood auctions

### Agency 51 Advertising

Account Executive

Philadelphia, PA June 2010 – January 2012

Consistently achieved quarterly goals and campaign success through measured reach of target audience as well as an increase in clients' customer base and sales

Collaborated with clients to develop and execute integrated creative campaigns for consumer and business-to-business marketing initiatives across print, broadcast,

#### Education

#### **Drexel University**

Philadelphia, PA

Graduated magna cum laude, June 2010

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Marketing Concentration, Communications Minor

Member of the Drexel Pennoni Honors College & Dean's Student Advisory Board

Received seven scholarships for academic excellence

## Entrepreneur

Wonder Valley Olive Oil Founder

Los Angeles, CA January 2014 – Present

Formulated the proprietary blend for Wonder Valley, an extra virgin olive oil from hand harvested Northern California olives; *available for sale Dec.* 2014

Taking this brand from ideation to execution through progressive branding and packaging design, website creation, sales management (both wholesale and direct to consumer), and developing a growth and sustainability strategy for the company's long term success

*à la Alison* www.alaalison.com *Creator* 

à la Alison connects travel storytelling with seasonal, regional recipes

Collaborations & recipe development for Barney's, Food 52, Refinery 29, Tomboy Style, and the Atlantic City Food & Wine Festival

# Skills & Activities

Freelance writer and photographer

Certified Yoga Alliance Instructor

Model for J. Crew, Mill Mercantile and RTH shop

electronic, and collateral media

Experienced photographer; trained in photo editing with Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop Elements

Proficient in Microsoft Office, website management, and HTML editing